Daniel Waterfield

Cambridge

UK

https://github.com/danwaterfield daniel.waterfield@gmail.com

Objective

Python developer looking for a first junior role after completing a PhD in 18th century history. Rare mix of technical and qualitative skills. A balanced portfolio of back-end and **full-stack** projects. Experienced in **communicating** complex ideas to non-specialist, international audiences.

Skills

- Comfortable: Python(numpy, pandas), GitHub, SQL.
- Familiar: Java, R, JS, Ruby, Rails. HTML/CSS, Flask, Django, AWS, Google Cloud.

Coding experience

Teaching myself full stack development. Emphasis on **Python** and Java, alongside Rails, JS, AWS and Google Cloud Vision mostly via codecademy and freecodecamp. **Algorithms** and **data structures** via Harvard's **CS50** lecture series, Princeton's Algorithms I coursera and textbooks. Portfolio on GitHub. Selected projects:

- 1. **British Voter Bot** (@voterbritish). **Collaboration** with a political scientist and a junior developer to source and write a **tweetbot in Python**. Posts user-friendly excerpts of anonymised voters from the British Electoral Survey, wave 13. Featured in Prospect Magazine.
- 2. **Evelina**. OCR **automated transcription of eighteenth-century handwriting**, extracting manuscript metadata for filtering and mapping correspondence networks. React with Google Cloud Vision integration.
- 3. **RailsBlog**. Basic **blog framework in js/html with Ruby on Rails** backend to familiarise self with rails and js to build a geolocation-based directory app to find autism-friendly spaces.

Work experience

Graduate Supervisor at University of Cambridge.

March 2018 - Present

Prepared and **taught seminars and gave lectures** to up to 15 first and third year undergraduates in historical theory. **Collaborated** with senior colleagues to tailor seminar reading, supervision guidance, and guide classroom discussion.

Gave one-to-one supervisions in European Political Philosophy 1700 - 1850. Set essay topics, assigned appropriate reading within strict time pressures, and gave student feedback.

Marketing and Social Media Assistant at Orange House Language School.

April 2015 – September 2015

Researched, compiled, and presented research on competitors to immediate manager and owner as this small business sought to expand into new premises and courses. Proposed and ran social media campaigns, tripling engagement. Ran front-desk part time, answering in-person enquiries, using English, French, and Bulgarian.

Education

University of Cambridge (Cambridge, UK)

Ph.D / Frances Burney d'Arblay and Anglican Womanhood, 1752 - 1840. October 2015 – Present

Wrote 80,000 word thesis on 18th century literature and politics, distilling 80 years of scholarship in 4 languages.

Learned **project management skills** as I took language classes, taught, researched and published an article and book reviews in top-ranked journals. Used my language skills to complete research trips to archives in London, Paris, The Vatican, Harvard, and Montreal. Presented my research to audiences of up to 100 people and won fellowships worth over £45,000.

University of Liverpool (Liverpool, UK.)

MA / Eighteenth-Century Worlds September 2013 – September 2014

Ran a francophone exchange evening, took modules in **economic**, social, and literary **history**, and wrote 15,000 word interdisciplinary dissertation on the novelist Frances Burney.

University of Liverpool (Liverpool, UK.)

B.A / English *March 2010 – July 2012*

Activities

Folk music (Fiddle); hiking; languages (EN/FR/DE/IT/ES, along with Latin and a little Bulgarian); writing (published in The Guardian, The Independent, Prospect, &c).